Milislav Demerec Papers 1919-1966 Mss.B.D394
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  - American Type Culture Collection, 1960; 3 items (Box 2)
  - American-Soviet Science Society, 1945; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Ames, G. F., 1963; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Edgar, 1931; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Anderson, E. G. (Ernest Gustav), 1924-1931; 30 items (Box 2)
    California Institute of Technology; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; Genetics -- Mutable genes; Genetics -- Variegation; Genetics of plants; Radiation genetics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Zea (maize) genetics
  - Anderson, E. S., 1957; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Thomas F, 1960; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Annual Review of Microbiology, 1952-1959; 16 items (Box 2)
  - Ansco Processing Laboratory, 1957; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Applied Microbiology, 1953; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Archives of Biochemistry, 1945; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics, 1953-1960; 6 items (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, Frank, 1961-1965; 21 item (Box 2)
  - Arnold, Ing Zdv, 1925; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Artschwager, Ernst, 1926-1935; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Artschwager, Richard, 1946; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Atomic Energy Commission, 1958-1964; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Auerbach, Charlotte, 1944-1948; 5 items (Box 2)
  - Austrian, Robert, 1958; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Automobile Club of New York, 1946; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Avery, George S., 1944-1954; 5 items (Box 2)
  - Avinoff, A., 1929-1933; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Babcock, E. B. (Ernest Brown), 1930-1946; 22 items (Box 2)
    Biographical and personal data -- Belling, John; Genetics of plants -- Crepis; Genetics of plants -- Delphinium; International Congress of Genetics; National Academy of Sciences
  - Balbinder, Elias, 1961-1963; 12 items (Box 2)
  - Ball, Meridian R., 1961-1962; 21 item (Box 2)
  - Banic, Stanko, 1950; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Banta, A. M., 1930-1940; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Bardes, William H., 1957; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Barnard College, 1944; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Barnes, B., 1930-1931; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Barrows, Florence L., 1930; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Bartlett, James H., 1943; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Bateson, Mrs. Beatrice, 1926; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Baudys, Ed, 1922-1924; 7 items (Box 2)
  - Bauer, Hans, 1940-1948; 8 items (Box 2)
  - Baur, Erwin, 1926-1931; 10 items (Box 2)
  - Bausch & Lomb Optical Company, 1925-1934; 19 items (Box 2)
  - Beadle, George Wells, 1929-1958; 2 folders (33 items) (Box 2)
    Biographical and personal data; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Drosophila genetics; Recommendations; Zea (maize) genetics
    - Folder 1, 1929-1930; 9 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1931-1958; 24 items (Box 2)
  - Bean, Barry, 1963; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Beh, Walter, 1947; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Belar, Karl, 1929; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Belling, John, 1931; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Benzin, Basil M., 1928; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Bernstein, Marianne, 1950; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bertani, G., 1955; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bertitio, Tihomil, 1949; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bevan, E. A., 1954; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bibliography of Demerec, 1921-1960; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Biesecker, E. B., 1943-1960; 7 items (Box 3)
  - Biographical material on applications, etc., for Demerec, 1942-1960; 9 items (Box 3)
  - Biographical sketch of Demerec, 1895-1960; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Biological Abstracts, 1946-1952; 20 items (Box 3)
  - Biological laboratory, 1940-1962; 4 folders (Box 3)
    Biographical and personal data -- Demerec, Milislav; Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Laboratory techniques, equipment
    - Folder 1, 1940; 9 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1941; 26 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 3, 1954-1962; 13 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 4, 1960; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Biological Reviews, 1946; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Birmingham, Lloyd, 1940; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Blaha, Jos., 1956; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Blakeslee, Albert Francis, 1927-1944; 6 folders (Box 3)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1927-1929; 7 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1934-1936; 44 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 3, 1937-1938; 19 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 4, 1939; 15 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 5, 1940; 20 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 6, 1941-1944; 14 items (Box 3)
  - Blaringhem, L., 1921; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bliss, C. I., 1944; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bodenstein, Dietrich, 1943; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Boericke & Tafel, 1944-1945; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Boivin, Mrs. A., 1948-1949; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bonnier, Gert, 1942-1956; 10 items (Box 3)
  - Born, Harold L., 1942; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Borntraeger, Gebrüder, 1929; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Borojevic, Katarina, 1965; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Borodin, D. N., 1926; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Botanical Review, 1945; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bose, Acharya Jagadish Chandra, 1958; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Botanical Society of America, Inc., 1959; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Botanicki Institut Univerze u Zagrebu, 1926-1927; 6 items (Box 3)
  - Boyd, William C., 1955; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Boyden, Alan, 1935; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Braun, Werner, 1955; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Bregger, Thomas, 1927; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Brenner, Sydney, 1955-1956; 12 items (Box 3)
  - Brewbaker, Harvey E., 1923; 14 items (Box 3)
  - Bridges, C. B. (Calvin B.), 1932-1949; 7 folders (Box 4)
    Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Publication; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1932-1934; 20 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1934; 15 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 3, 1934-1938; 36 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 4, 1938-1939; 25 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 5, 1939; 33 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 6, 1940-1942; 21 item (Box 4)
    - Folder 7, 1943-1949; 32 items (Box 4)
  - Brieger, F. G., 1928-1932; 4 items (Box 4)
  - Brink, R. Alexander, 1925-1947; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Folder 1, 1925-1926; 8 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1929-1947; 13 items (Box 4)
  - Brito da Cunha, A., 1958; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Bronk, Detlev W., 1953-1960; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Brookhaven Laboratory Personnel, 1959-1964; 2 folders (Box 4)
    Graduate study; Recommendations
    - Folder 1, 1959-1963; 26 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1962-1964; 12 items (Box 4)
  - Brookhaven Laboratory Reports, 1961-1966; 3 folders (Box 4)
    Bacterial genetics; Business -- Reports; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Political issues; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1963-1966; 16 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1963-1965; 12 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 3, 1961-1963; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Brookhaven Laboratory Staff Manual, 1963; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Brozek, Arthur, 1926-1933; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Brunson, A. M., 1923-1930; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Brunst, Victor, 1924-1946; 5 items (Box 4)
  - Buck, ?, 1939; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Burnham, Charles R., 1926-1936; 7 items (Box 4)
  - Bunker, Frank F., 1933; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Bush, Vannevar, 1939-1956; 14 items (Box 4)
    Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data -- Demerec, Milislav; Biographical and personal data -- Muller, Hermann Joseph; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
  - Butler, E. G., 1960; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Butler, J. A. V., 1951; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Buzzati-Traverso, A. A., 1945-1950; 20 items (Box 4)
  - Camara, A., 1946; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Cancer research, 1946-1957; 12 folders (Box 4)
    Bacterial genetics; Business; Cancer, chemotherapy -- Chemical mutagens; Drosophila genetics; Fellowships, assistantships; Publication; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1949-1953; 15 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1955-1956; 13 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 3, 1953-1957; 33 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 4, 1946-1954; 23 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 5, 1953-1954; 19 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 6, 1952-1953; 16 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 7, 1950-1952; 36 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 8, 1946-1947; 53 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 9, 1947-1948; 35 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 10, 1948-1949; 22 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 11, 1949-1950; 17 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 12, 1949; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Carl Zeiss, Inc., 1926; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Carlson, J. G., 1966; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1923; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Carvalho, Alcides, 1959; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Carver, W. A., 1924-1925; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Caspersson, T., 1947; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Caspari, Ernst W., 1955-1960; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Castle, W. E., 1933-1948; 5 items (Box 5)
  - Catcheside, D. G., 1937-1951; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Cattell, J McKeen, 1925-1935; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Cavalli-Sforza, L. L., 1955-1956; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Cekie, F. W., n.d.; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Central Scientific Company, 1923; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Chardon, Carlos E., 1928; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Chemical Mutations - Cancer Society, 1954; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Chen, Kuo-chun, 1963; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Childs, J. D., 1964-1965; 9 items (Box 5)
  - Chino, M., 1930-1933; 8 items (Box 5)
  - Chovnick, Arthur, 1939; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Christow, M., 1926; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Chromeres, Jag Jan, 1924; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Clark, Hugh, 1959; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Cleland, Ralph E., 1929-1950; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Clowes, R. C., 1962-1964; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Cmelik, S., 1953; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Cole, L. J., 1929; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Collector of Customs, 1952; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Collier's, 1944; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Columbia University, 1942-1963; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Folder 1, 1942-1945; 11 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1945-1951; 19 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 3, 1952-1963; 29 items (Box 5)
  - Condon, Edward U, 1947-1948; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, 1958; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Conferences, 1939-1965
    Bacterial genetics; Cancer, chemotherapy; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Drosophila genetics; Evolution; Genetics; International Congress of Genetics -- Ninth Congress; Invitations; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Conferences: 1939-1945, 41 items (Box 5)
    - Conferences: 1950, 35 items (Box 5)
    - Conferences: 1951, 55 items (Box 5)
    - Conferences: 1952, 59 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1953, 14 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1954, 50 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1955, 36 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1956, 52 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1957, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Folder 1, 1957; 71 items (Box 6)
      - Folder 2, 1957; 50 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1958, 41 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1959, 54 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1960, 52 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: 1964-1965, 10 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: The Nature of the Gene. Western Reserve. Oct. 10-12, 1960, 3 items (Box 6)
    - Conferences: Puerto Rico, 1962, 8 items (Box 6)
  - Congratulatory letters to and from Demerec, 1941-1960; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Folder 1, 1941-1946; 34 items (Box 6)
    - Folder 2, 1946-1960; 26 items (Box 6)
  - Constantinescu, G. K., 1946-1947; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Cook, Robert C., 1928-1953; 4 folders (Box 7)
    Drosophila Information Service; Editorial matters -- Journal of Heredity; Muller, Hermann Joseph
    - Folder 1, 1928-1933; 28 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1931-1935; 20 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1935-1936; 28 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1937-1953; 48 items (Box 7)
  - Cooper, H. P., 1925; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Cooper, Kenneth, 1955; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Cori, Carl F., 1940; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Corner, George W., 1941; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Corson, Dale R., 1964; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Cotterman, Charles W., 1944; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Cranach, 1927; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Curtis, Howard J., 1962-1963; 6 items (Box 7)
  - Curtis, Otis F., 1927; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dahlberg, G., 1945; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dale, E. E., 1929-1932; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Darby, H. H., 1936; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Darlington, C. D., 1929-1940; 14 items (Box 7)
  - Davenport, Charles B., 1921-1942; 2 folders (Box 7)
    Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; International Congress of Genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication; Research support
    - Folder 1, 1921-1930; 27 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1931-1942; 19 items (Box 7)
  - Davey, A. J., n.d.; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Davidson, J. B., 1923; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Davis, Donald W., 1932; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dayton, Irving E., 1949; 1 item (Box 7)
  - DeKanovic, Anton, 1923-1926; 6 items (Box 7)
  - Delbrück, M., 1946-1953; 6 items (Box 7)
  - Demerec, Milislav, 1922; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Demerec, Milislav: Reprints 1958-1968, 1 item (Box 7)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also Series V.
    Bibliographical matters
  - Dempster, Everett, 1941; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Devereux, E. D., 1959; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Dillman, A. C., 1932; 5 items (Box 7)
  - Dillon, T. H., 1940-1941; 6 items (Box 7)
  - Dippernaar, B. J., 1931; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1929-1957; 7 folders (172 items) (Box 7)
    Atomic Energy Commission; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Evolution; International Congress of Genetics; Population genetics; Publication; Research support; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1929-1933; 20 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1933-1934; 16 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 3, 1934-1936; 26 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 4, 1936-1937; 31 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 5, 1937-1939; 22 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 6, 1939-1943; 36 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 7, 1944-1957; 21 items (Box 7)
  - Dobzhansky, Mrs. T. G., 1930-1949; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Dodge, B. O., 1937-1938; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Donella Pontiac Co., 1956; 1 item (Box 7)
  - Dreyfus, A., 1943-1944; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Dreyfuss, Jacques, 1963; 3 items (Box 7)
  - Drosophila Information Service, 1934-1960; 2 folders (Box 7)
    Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1934-1960; 34 items (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1934; 23 items (Box 7)
  - Drosophila Stock Center...Organization and support, 1934-1943; 2 folders (Box 8)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics; Drosophila Information Service; Research support; Rockefeller Foundation
    - Folder 1, 1939-1943; 25 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1934-1939; 40 items (Box 8)
  - Dubinin, N., 1946; 2 items (Box 8)
  - DuBois, Anne Marie, 1932; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Dunkerson, Patricia S., 1937; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Dunn, Leslie Clarence, 1933-1955; 35 items (Box 8)
    Columbia University; Mouse genetics; Publication; Recommendations; Referee's report; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Dunn, Louise, 1960; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Dushmon, Miriam B., 1961; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Dyson-Hudson, V. R. D., 1954-1955; 5 items (Box 8)
  - E. R. Squibb, and Sons, 1958; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Eames, Arthur J., 1930; 2 items (Box 8)
  - East, E. M., 1927-1937; 14 items (Box 8)
  - Echenhofer, Janey, 1962; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Eigsti, O J, 1938-1955; 4 items (Box 8)
  - Eisenstarck, A., 1961-1966; 17 items (Box 8)
  - Emerson, R. A. (Rollins Adams), 1923-1947; 2 folders (110 items) (Box 8)
    Drosophila genetics; Genetics; Genetics of plants -- Delphinium; Mangelsdorf, Paul C.; Publication; Zea (maize) genetics
    - Folder 1, 1923-1925; 58 items (Box 8)
    - Folder 2, 1926-1947; 52 items (Box 8)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1959; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1955; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Englesberg, E., 1960; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Enzmann, E. V., 1937; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Ephrussi, Boris, 1934-1961; 40 items (Box 8)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Ercegovic, Miho, 1926-1936; 9 items (Box 8)
  - Erikesen, K. R., 1948; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Erlanson, Carl O., 1929; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Erlanson, Eileen W., 1930; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Ernst, A., 1951-1958; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Eyster, William H., 1920-1931; 9 items (Box 8)
  - Faberge, A. C., 1943-1957; 15 items (Box 8)
  - Fabius & Co., Inc., 1957; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Failla, G., 1937-1938; 5 items (Box 8)
  - Fano, U. (Ugo), 1940-1950; 20 items (Box 8)
    Biographical and personal data; Radiation genetics; Research support
  - Farrow, John G., 1930-1934; 20 items (Box 8)
  - Feehan, Frances, 1924-1933; 9 items (Box 8)
  - Felix, E. L., 1929; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Fellowship Committees, 1961-1962; 6 items (Box 8)
  - Fellowships, 1935-1941; 42 items (Box 8)
    Fellowships, assistantships -- Buck, John B.; Fellowships, assistantships -- Delbruck, Max; Fellowships, assistantships -- Gustafsson, Ake; Fellowships, assistantships -- Hoecker, Frank E.; Fellowships, assistantships -- Slizynski, B. M.; Fellowships, assistantships -- Westergaard, Morgens
  - Fenton, C. L., 1934; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fernald, E. J., 1930; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fish and Wild Life Service, 1946; 1 item (Box 8)
  - Fisher, R. A., 1931-1932; 7 items (Box 8)
  - Fitzhugh, W. F., 1924; 2 items (Box 8)
  - Flagg, Robert, 1953; 3 items (Box 8)
  - Fleming, John A., 1933-1935; 7 items (Box 8)
  - Fogg, John M., 1956; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Ford, E. B., 1948-1957; 4 items (Box 9)
  - Franges, Ivan, 1930-1936; 6 items (Box 9)
  - Frankel, O. H., 1956-1957; 5 items (Box 9)
  - Frazer, Allan C., 1924-1940; 21 items (Box 9)
  - French Lines, 1957; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Fricke, Hugo, 1938-1946; 4 items (Box 9)
  - Fujii, K., 1929-1934; 7 items (Box 9)
  - Fulbright Program, 1957; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Funk, F. James, 1959-1961; 7 items (Box 9)
  - Gaddis, Hamilton, 1955; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Gamow, George, 1947-1953; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Garber, R. J., 1933-1952; 3 items (Box 9)
  - Geesh, Eileen, 1960; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Geigy, R., 1932; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Gene Conference, 2nd. 1938, 12 items (Box 9)
  - Gene Conference, 3rd. 1940, 23 items (Box 9)
  - "Gene Study", 1934-1937; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Folder 1, 1934-1936; 33 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 2, 1934-1937; 15 items (Box 9)
  - "Gene Study" organization, n.d.; 0 items (Box 9)
    Papers missing.
  - General Biological Supply House, Inc., 1942; 1 item (Box 9)
  - Genetical Society of Great Britain, 1952; 2 items (Box 9)
  - Genetics Congress, 8th, 1945-1960; 6 folders (Box 9)
    Bacterial genetics; Conferences and symposia; Drosophila Information Service; International Congress of Genetics -- Eighth Congress; Publication; Russian politics and science; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Genetics Congress, 8th. Permanent International Committee., 1945-1946; 21 items (Box 9)
    - Genetics Congress, 8th. Travel Committee., 1941-1960; 5 folders (Box 9)
      - Folder 1, 1947-1960; 23 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 2, 1948; 21 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 3, 1947-1948; 28 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 4, 1941-1948; 36 items (Box 9)
      - Folder 5, 1947; 20 items (Box 9)
  - Genetics Congress, 10th, 1952-1957; 7 Folders (Box 9)
    Business; Conferences and symposia; International Congress of Genetics -- Tenth Congress; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1952-1954; 48 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 2, 1954-1955; 30 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 3, 1955; 25 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 4, 1955-1956; 20 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 5, 1955-1957; 18 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 6, 1956-1957; 41 items (Box 9)
    - Folder 7, 1956-1957; 28 items (Box 9)
  - Genetics Congress, 11th, 1960; 18 items (Box 10)
  - Genetics (Journal), 1944-1966; 2 folders (Box 10)
    Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data -- Blakeslee, Albert Francis; Drosophila genetics; Publication -- Genetics; Radiation genetics; Referee's report
    - Folder 1, 1944-1959; 49 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1960-1966; 20 items (Box 10)
  - Genetics Society, 1937-1949; 2 folders (Box 10)
    Bibliographical matters; Editorial matters; Genetics Society of America; International Congress of Genetics; Publication; Scientific refugees
    - Folder 1, 1937-1940; 31 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1941-1949; 17 items (Box 10)
  - Genetic tests (charts), n.d.; 2 items (Box 10)
  - George Banta Publishing Company, 1926-1928; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Gershenson, S., 1933; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gilbert, W. M. (Walter M.), 1926-1945; 2 folders (Box 10)
    Bacterial genetics; Biographical and personal data -- Bridges, Calvin B.; Biographical and personal data -- Sutton, Eileen; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Drosophila genetics
    - Folder 1, 1926-1938; 20 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1939-1945; 18 items (Box 10)
  - Giles, Norman H., 1964; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gillespie, David H., 1962-1963; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Glass, H. Bentley, 1951-1959; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Gloor, W. E., 1957; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Godfrey, William S. Jr., 1956; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Goldschmidt, Richard B., 1941-1951; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Gologan, V., 1936; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Goodrich, H. B., 1936; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Gordon, Myron, 1941-1942; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Gots, Joseph S., 1961-1964; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Gottschewski, G. H. M., 1947; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Gowen, John W., 1925-1953; 23 items (Box 10)
  - Grace, Edwin J., 1945-1962; 26 items (Box 10)
  - Grant, Madeleine P., 1951-1952; 9 items (Box 10)
  - Gray, Thomas C., 1964; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Green, M. M., 1956; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Gregoric, Pavle, 1952-1953; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Griffen, 1947; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Griggs, Robert F., 1947; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Grkovic, Milan, 1953; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Grüneberg, H., 1940; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Györffy, Barna, 1957; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Haan, H de, 1931-1932; 5 items (Box 10)
  - Haase-Bessell, G., 1931; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Hackstaff, Betty, 1934; 2 items (Box 10)
  - Hackett, L. W., 1937; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Haddow, Alexander, 1953-1954; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Hadorn, Ernst, 1945; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Hall, H M, 1930-1931; 4 items (Box 10)
  - Haldane, J. B. S., 1931-1961; 6 items (Box 10)
  - Hansen, Arne, 1959; 1 item (Box 10)
  - Hanson, Frank Blair, 1924-1944; 2 folders (Box 10)
    Recommendations -- Carlson, Elof Axel; Recommendations -- Fano, Ugo; Recommendations -- Harnley, Morris H.; Recommendations -- Huskins, C. Leonard; Recommendations -- Slizynski, B. M.; Recommendations -- Spencer, Warren P.; Recommendations -- Waddington, Conrad Hal; Research support; Rockefeller Foundation
    - Folder 1, 1935-1944; 30 items (Box 10)
    - Folder 2, 1927-1934; 5 items (Box 10)
  - Harris, J. Arthur, 0 items (Box 10)
  - Harris, Reginald G., 1928-1934; 3 items (Box 10)
  - Hartman, Philip E., 1963-1966; 3 folders (Box 11)
    Fellowships, assistantships; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1966; 32 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 2, 1966; 21 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 3, 1963-1964; 6 items (Box 11)
  - Hartman, Philip E. "Nomenclature", 1963-1966; 5 folders (Box 11)
    Bacterial genetics -- Nomenclature
    - Folder 1, 1965-1966; 10 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 2, 1965; 6 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 3, 1963; 16 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 4, 1963-1966; 7 items (Box 11)
    - Folder 5, 1966; 7 items (Box 11)
  - Hartmann, Max, 1946; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Haskins, Caryl P., 1959-1960; 26 items (Box 11)
    Bacterial genetics; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
  - Hayer, Helen S., 1931; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Hayes, H. K., 1928-1931; 8 items (Box 11)
  - Hayes, William, 1955-1966; 10 items (Box 11)
  - Henderson, A. D., 1945; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Henke, K., 1948; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Henshaw, Paul S., 1939; 5 items (Box 11)
  - Hersh, A H, 1930; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hershey, A. D., 1947; 4 items (Box 11)
  - Herskowitz, I. H., 1950; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Herzog, n.d.; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Hevesy, George, 1948; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Heys, Florence M., 1939; 3 items (Box 11)
  - Hickson, Fred T., 1953; 5 items (Box 11)
  - Hieger, I., 1948; 2 items (Box 11)
  - Hill, Henry E., 1929; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Hiorth, Gunnar, 1950; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Hinton, Taylor, 1951; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Hlakuth, Mladen, 1925; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Hoffer, G. N., 1925; 2 items (Box 11)